It's time we knew
Detroit is a drama, thriller, history film directed by Kathryn Bigelow.
A police raid in Detroit in 1967 results in one of the largest
citizens' uprisings in the history of the United States.
Melvin Dismukes, played by John Boyega.
Philip Krauss, played by Will Poulter.
Greene, played by Anthony Mackie.
Larry Reed, played by Algee Smith.
Julie Ann, played by Hannah Murray.
Carl Cooper, played by Jason Mitchell.
Detroit is a 2017 American historical crime drama film directed
by Kathryn Bigelow and written by Mark Boal.
It stars John Boyega, Will Poulter, Algee Smith, Jason
Mitchell, John Krasinski, and Anthony Mackie.
Based on the Algiers Motel incident during Detroit's 1967 12th Street Riot, the
film's release commemorated the 50th anniversary of the event.
The film premiered at Detroit's Fox Theatre on July 25, 2017, and began a limited
theatrical release on July 28, before opening wide on August 4.
It received positive reviews from critics, with particular praise given to Bigelow's direction, Boal's script, and the performances of
Poulter, Boyega, and Smith, but was a box office failure, only grossing $24 million against its $34 million budget.
The film explores themes of fire, police brutality,
church choir, based on true story, beating.
The tone is intense and dark and emotional.